Andrew Luetkemeier

UX / UI Designer

Creative UI Designer with 1 years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software in the professional scene, with 6 years of training and out-of-work experience. Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principals and related development goals. Dedicated to creating inviting and unintimidating interfaces for everything from simple open-source applications to complex proprietary systems.

Work History

2021-05 -Current

UX/UI Designer

MidwayUSA, COLUMBIA, MO

- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Evaluated user research to convert abstract ideas and requirements into planning tools such as journey maps, user personas and storyboards.
- Collaborated with SLT to integrate UI features complying with prescribed code standards and technical design guidelines.
- Devised site maps, user flows, wireframes and mockups for designs based on proven methodologies, stakeholder requests and end-user feedback.
- Utilized Google Analytics to monitor websites and other digital content and recommended strategies and updated channels to improve performance.
- Researched and proposed new solutions to make website more user-friendly.

2018-01 -2021-05

Kitchen Staff Member

Lutz's Famous BBQ, COLUMBIA, MO

Maintained records of purchases using approved

Contact

Address

COLUMBIA, MO, 65203

Phone

(573) 825-5619

E-mail

andrewwluetkemeier@gma il.com

Skills

User Interface (UI) design



SASS



HTMI



Adobe CC



Collaboration



Research



- invoice tracking tools and conducted regular inventory counts of food, tools and supplies.
- Sanitized dining ware and kitchen equipment according to health code standards.
- Made food according to standard recipes with requested changes for customer satisfaction.
- Maintained clean, trash-free workspaces to maximize productivity and safety.
- Learned other teammates' work tasks to train as backup.

Education

2020-08 - Bachelor's: Web Design

Current
University of Missouri - Columbia - Columbia, MO

2018-08 - Associate of Arts: General Studies

2020-05 Moberly Area Community College - Columbia, MO

Accomplishments

- Dean's List University of Missouri Fall Semester 2020
- Eagle Scout Award from the Boy Scouts of America through Troop 4, Columbia Missouri - 2016

Certifications

2016-10 Adobe Photoshop

2016-10 Adobe Illustrator

2016-10 Adobe After Effects

Interests

Creating simple beautiful User Interfaces

Hiking / Nature Photography

Computer building / Gaming